迈克 · 诺斯: 我们来看看一些更高级的类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We're gonna take
a look at some more advanced types.
我知道看起来我们已经走在了前面
I know it seems like we've already been
in advanced having gone through with
仿制药。
a generics.
但是我希望你们能够了解什么是可能的，因为你们学到了更多
But I want you to get a sense for
what's possible as you learn more and
更多关于如何用打字稿设计有效的约束。
more about how to design effective
constraints with typescript.
迈克 · 诺斯: 首先我们来看看映射类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: First we're
gonna look at mapped types.
这涉及到使用一个接口作为
And this involves using an interface as
一种从接口键到与这些键相关联的类型的方法。
a way from getting to the interfaces keys
to the types associated with those keys.
所以我们在之前的工作室里有一个功能
So we had a function
earlier in the workshop
我们试图通过电话或电子邮件联系人们。
where we were trying to contact
people by phone or email.
我们使用重载，我们使用多个函数签名,
And we used overloads,
we use multiple functions signatures,
为了确保那封邮件，一封有电子邮件和电话，一封有电话。
in order to insure that email,
one with email and phone, one with phone.
这将需要新的通信方法的增加,
This will require as new
communications methods were added,
will 需要更多的签名，对吧？
will requires to add more signatures,
right?
第一个参数和第二个参数一起耦合，每个新参数一个。
One for each new, coupling of the first
and the second parameter together.
所以我们将使用 map 类型来完成类似的事情。
So we are going to use map type
to accomplish similar thing.
Mike North: 这是一个新的函数，叫做 contact,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So here is a new function,
it's called contact,
它的类型参数必须从上面接口的键扩展。
it has a type parameter that must extend
from a key of the above interface.
有没有人有这样的预感，这可能意味着什么？
Anyone have a hunch as to what
the possible values of that could be?
演讲者2: 电子邮件，电话，传真麦克 · 诺斯: 电子邮件，电话,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Email ,phone, fax
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Email, phone,
传真，谢谢。
fax, thank you.
所以电子邮件，电话，传真，还有
So email, phone, and fax, and
然后我们采用这种类型，这就是它成为地图类型的原因。
then we're taking that type and
this is what makes it a map type.
我们将这个密钥传递到接口中，然后
We're passing that key into the interface,
and
我们将得到与该键相关的对应值。
we'll get the corresponding
value associated with that key.
所以这三个都可以，但是
So here these three will all work, but
如果我试图逆转事情，像使用电话在这里我们会得到
if I were to try to reverse things
like use phone up here we're gonna get
和函数签名的错误是一样的。
the same kinds of errors that we were
getting with the function signatures.
第一个参数和第二个参数必须一致。
The first parameter and
the second parameter must agree.
但是在我看来，这个更容易维护，因为
But in my opinion, this is a little
bit easier to maintain because for
新的通信方式，我们只需要添加一种新的道路的接口。
new communication methods we only need to
add a sort of a new road to the interface.
更重要的是，我们可以使用这种产品，我们可以消费这种产品
And what's more, we could use this,
we could consume this type and
在我们的应用程序中做许多不同的事情的地图。
do this mapping across many
different things in our app.
所以如果你有一些不同类型的概念
So if you have some concept
like the different types of
你可以从你的 API 中获得的模型,
models that you can get from your API,
你可以用名字来指代它们，然后你就可以得到正确的字体了。
and you want to refer to them by name, and
then you can get that correct type back.
你可以有一个真理的来源，在那里所有这一切都得到维护
You can have one source of truth
where all of this is maintained and
然后其他所有的东西都以这种方式消耗地图的类型。
then everything else that consumes
the map's type in this way.
他们可以
They can
自动获得更新，因为它们是用一个接口来表示的。
automatically get updated because they're
expressed in terms of that one interface.
所以就像在价值世界里，这是，对不起，我在这里滚动。
So it's just like in the value world,
this is taking, sorry, I'm scrolling here.
在 JavaScript 值的世界中，这只是获取一个键和
In the JavaScript values world,
this is just taking a key and
将其传递给对象以获取其值，语法是相同的。
passing it into an object to get its
value, and the syntax is the same.
所以我把它想象成物体。
So I just think of this like objects.
就像你说的这里有钥匙,
So as you said, the available keys here,
电子邮件、电话或传真等通讯方式的关键。
a key of communication methods email,
phone, or fax.
我们甚至可以通过获取这些键和
We can even get all values
by taking these keys and
把他们三个人的影子投射到
projecting the set of
the three of them through
接口来获取所有可能的值。
the interface to get all
of the possible values.
有电子邮件编号或传真，这是所有这三个在这里。
HasEmail of HasPhoneNumber or fax,
that is all three of these up here.
所以如果你有任何东西，你有 a 或者 b 或者 c
So if you have anything that were
you've got a or b, or c, and
通过接口，你会得到相应的值的关键或
pass it through interface, you'll get
the corresponding value of that key or
另一个键的值，或者第三个键的值，对吗？
value of the other key, or
the value of the third key, right?
迈克 · 诺斯: 很酷，我的意思是看起来你希望它能成功,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Pretty cool, I mean it
seems like you would hope it would work,
的确如此。
and it does.
键入查询、颜色和提前概念，但
Type queries, a colors,
and advance concept, but
理解起来相对简单 typeof 允许我们得到
it's relatively simple to understand,
typeof allows us to get
一个符号的类型，一个值的类型。
the type of a symbol,
the type of a value I should say.
在 JavaScript 中，Symbol 是一个非常重载的术语。
Symbol is a very overloaded
term in JavaScript.
这里我们得到了一个值，它的类型是一个解析为一个数字的承诺。
So here we've got a value whose type
is a promise that resolves to a number.
而且我可以得到承诺的类型，决心有喜欢的
And I can get the typeof what
promise that resolve has like
这个函数的类型，我可以得到
the type of this function here,
I can kind of acquire that
在类型别名的上下文中使用运算符的类型。
by using the type of operator
in the context of a type alias.
你也可以这样做。
You could do the same thing like this.
迈克 · 诺斯: 嗯，我喜欢这样做，但是这就对了。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Well,
I do it like let, but there you go.
这就是所谓的类型查询，因为你正在查询这个值的类型。
So this is called a type query cuz you're
kind of querying for this values type.
Mike North: 条件类型这是在类型脚本2.8中添加的，非常漂亮
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Conditional types this was
added in types script 2.8 which is pretty
最近的。
recent.
这是用于类型的 tunnery 操作符。
This is a tunnery operator for types.
所以我们这里有一个泛型，您只能在泛型中使用它们。
So we've got a generic here,
you can only use them with generics.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们的意思是，我们希望基本上抓住一个承诺的类型，或者
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We're saying we want to
basically grab the type of a promise, or
如果不是一个承诺，就让它直接通过。
let something pass straight
through if it's not a promise.
所以这就像，给我最终的价值，这将变成和
So this is like, give me the eventual
value that this will turn into and
如果不是承诺，那就是价值本身。
if it's not a promise,
that is the value itself.
所以我们引入了一个 t 型，如果 t 从 Promise 延伸出来,
So we take in a type T,
if T extends from Promise,
提取出承诺解析的类型，我们在这里使用推断。
extract out the type that the Promise
resolves to, we use infer here.
这是唯一可以使用推断的地方，但是
This is the only place you can use infer,
but
它让你拿出类型的承诺决心。
it let's you pluck out the type
the Promise resolves to.
所以如果 t 从承诺延伸出来,
So if T extends from Promise,
返回它的结果，否则，让我们只是直接通过。
return what it results to, otherwise,
just let is sail straight through.
在这里，我们可以看到 a 是数字类型。
And here,
we can see that a is of type number.
我们说的是 EventualType 的承诺数字。
We're saying EventualType
of Promise number.
一个数字的出现是因为我们在遵循真实的条款。
A number comes out cuz we're following
we're in the truthy clause here.
在 b 中，我们可以看到数字数组有点直接通过，对吗？
In b we can see that the number array
kinda sails straight through, right?
因为它跟着这根树枝走下去。
Cuz it's following this branch down here.